Shaquil Hansford



liuqahs15@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/shaquil-hansford



Phone Number Available At Request



https://www.shaquilhansford.com/

Summary

With 10 years of personal experience writing code, and over one year of web development with personal projects, I've built strong skills in JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3. My specialties are jQuery, React, Express, MongoDB and Node.js. I am a Full Stack Developer seeking a full-time, part time, contract or temporary position at a growing company. Some of my other skills include GraphQL, Redis, Socket.io, Passport.js, and the YouTube API.

My non-developer technical skills include Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere, and Adobe After Effects. My nontechnical skills include Japanese, Video Editing and Graphic Design.

I offer strong communication, a focus on understanding and satisfying customer needs, and experience working remote as a freelancer.

My CV:

http://shaquilhansford.com/shaquilhansford_cv.pdf

Experience



Video Director

Self Employed

2017 - 2021 (5 years)

As a self-employed video editor and director, I had to handle production tasks at all levels of the process. This included storyboarding, location-searching, equipment management, video direction, video editing, and other major skills.

- Discovered and acquired customers through active cold-calls, emails and advertisements.
- Worked with customers to plan shooting schedules, video concepts and budgets.
- Directed and filmed music videos at various locations.
- Edited videos to customer-specified requirements.
- Worked in Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, and Adobe Photoshop

Freelance Graphic Designer

Self-employed

2017 - Present (4 years 3 months +)

As a self-employed designer, it was my job to handle all aspects of the business. This included acquiring customers, working with them to determine their needs, and providing them with marketready, professional end-products.

Sought out customers through cold-calls, emails, and advertisements.

- Communicated back and forth with customers until their requirements were clear and the project could be started.
- Worked with customers to adjust each draft in the process to their desires.
- Produced web presences for clients, including social media images, album cover arts, and promotional posters.
- Used Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere and Adobe After Effects

70) Retail Sales Associate

Walgreens

2012 - 2017 (6 years)

As a sales associate for Walgreens, I juggled many different roles. This often occurred at an understaffed location where I had to react to situations immediately, autonomously, and appropriately

- Guided customers through finding good discounts and deals to maximize their purchases.
- De-escalated situations with stressed customers and resolved their issues.
- Organized stock rooms and shelves for efficiency and cleanliness.
- Handled high volumes of customers during peak-traffic hours.

Education



WP William Paterson University of New Jersey

Computer Science

2010 - 2014

Still not complete. Took academic hiatus due to family health and financial issues.

Skills

Interpersonal Skills • Node.js • React.js • Express.js • MongoDB • JavaScript • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Redis • YouTube API